Hvað er það?
On a cross and were buried in a grave, laid there by mortals you have made, though by
your word had the universe been created.
Therefore, when you shackled the enemy,
wandering his kingdom and spirit,
boiling him.
Down in Hades,
everyone cried out to you
as they saw your life,
life bringing rising.
Christ is risen,
who is forever,
the giver of life everlasting.
Both now and forever into the ages of ages of men.
Come believers, let us see where Christ the Savior has been born.
Let us follow where the star guides us with magi from the east.
Then choirs of angels unceasingly sing their praises.
Shepherds of the Lord
and their flocks in the fields abide,
offering them praise and upfitting hymn,
singing the anthem, glory in the highest
to the one born in a cave to death.
From her, the mother of God,
on her
In Bethlehem of Trudelion.
You rose the immortal one out of the grave as true God.
You raised with you the universe by your return from the dead.
O Christ, our deliverer, triumphing by your power over Hades' dominion,
showing your great compassion for all things by your rising.
Therefore, we worship you, alone are the friend of man.
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
and
the
Oh
He'll give you hope.
Both now and ever into the ages of ages.
Amen.
Mary, why are you amazed at what is taking place in you?
Because I gave birth in time to an eternal son, she says.
but I do
do not understand how he was conceived in me.
I have not known man, how then can I bear a son
who has ever seen birth without man see?
But as it is written, where God so wills,
the order of
all
nature is overcome
for Christ is born
from the blessed
virgin in Bethlehem
of Judea
Oh
O Lord, teach me your truths.
Why do you mingle sweet spices with your tears, O women disciples?
that
The wrestling angel in the tomb said to the myrrh-bearing women,
Behold the tomb and under the Savior has risen from the grave.
O Lord, teach me your statutes.
Lama
Bearing women, coming with spices to your grateful Savior.
Heard an angel saying to them, Why do you number living with the dead?
For as good he has risen from the dead.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Both now and forever, until the ages of ages, amen.
By giving birth to the giver of life, you redeemed Adam from sin, O virgin.
and you brought deep joy instead of sorrow.
He who was incarnate from you.
who is both God and man, has guided back to life
those who have fallen from life.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia,
alleluia, alleluia, alleluia,
Glory to you, O God.
Alleluia, alleluia, alleluia,
Lord, shall see you at all.
Alleluia, alleluia.
And yet, yet, we shall pray through.
Lord, have mercy.
Oh
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Remembering our most holy, immaculate, most blessed and glorious Lady,
the Theotokos and our Virgin Mary, with all the saints,
let us command ourselves and one another and our whole life to Christ our God.
For blessed is your name and glorified is your kingdom of the Father,
I don't know.
Son and Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
The murder is proclaimed to the apostles,
the news of your wondrous rise and your prize,
that as God you have risen, granting the world your great mercy.
.
Oh, you hate Zion.
May you be put to shame by the Lord,
or you will be dried up as grass by fire.
Thank you.
Divine ears are given even to me.
I'm the Lord of the Lord of the Lord.
Martin, Megan, Brian, children.
Glory to the Father, into the Son, into the Holy Spirit,
and the Lord of the Lord.
by the warning
the streams of grace well water water being all creation to engender life
As one who has tendered love for my
the
of ages, amen.
By the Holy Spirit
comes wealth and
divine knowledge,
contemplation and
wisdom, for by him
the word of
the father's teaching
arise lord help us and redeem us
for the glory of your name.
this is
this
james
James, Sarah Lee.
Ση Κύριε Αναγία
το Πατρί και το Υιό και το Υιό Πνεύμα την οικία και εις τους αιώνας των αιώνων.
Αμήν.
Ο Σωτήρ και Βυστισμού από το τάφος,
ο Θεός ανέστησε εκ των θεσμών τους
η γενής και πύλας άγους συνέθλιψε
και ο Θεσπούτησαν έστη τριμερός.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Let all of us who are born on earth sing the praise of Christ, the giver of life,
who rose from the dead on the third day from the tomb,
and by his power today smashed the gates of death,
put Hades to death, and crushed the sting of death,
set Adam free with Eve, as with thanksgiving we cry aloud our fervent praise,
for he is alone the mighty God,
and Master rose on the third day.
I'm a composer, Peter.
of the day.
.
in the morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the
morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the morning, and the
O Lord of mercy, save us who honor you.
By the ineffable will, born in the flesh is the fleshless one.
In body, now circumscribed, is the uncircumscribed,
immutably preserving both essences.
An origin receives he who in nature is unoriginate
and alone transcends time.
As an infant is perceived, he who transcends perfection.
or
Born in arms is he who bears the universe.
Therefore, as God, by his birth, he crowns those who have the honor of being his kin.
Whom we glorify with faith as we cry without ceasing.
O Lord of mercy, save us who honor you.
On December 28th, we commemorate the holy 20,000 who burned in Nicodemus.
media. On this day, we also commemorate the holy martyrs who were in the Senate, who fled from the
fire, died. Saint Indos died by drowning in the sea. Saints Gorgon and Peter died in the sea.
The holy martyr Zeno died by the sword. The holy martyr Mardonios died by fire. Saint Dorotheos,
the courtier, died by the sword. Saint Theophilus, the deacon, died by stoning.
Saint McDonough.
died by being burned in a pit.
Saint Glicarius, the priest, died by fire.
On this day, Saint Domna was cut by the sword
and died by fire.
The devout Saint Simon the Myrstreamer,
the founder of the holy monastery of Simonopetra
on Athos reposed in peace.
On this Sunday after Christmas,
we also commemorate the holy and righteous ancestors of God,
Joseph, the betrothed of Our Lady the Lord.
the Holy Theotokos, and Virgin Mary,
James, or Jacobos,
the brother of the Lord,
and David, the prophet and king.
By the intercessions of your saints, O God,
have mercy on us and save us. Amen.
Amen.
O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O Lord, O
God, good one,
humiliating
the faithful look
of the foe.
Blessed Lord,
who see all things
above all sin,
now raise us up,
us up, establish us,
your faithful
singers,
resolute and firm
upon the sure
base of faith.
Once was
up
prophet, have a
comb counted worthy,
passed all expression to see
Christ's birth depicted.
And he foretold
singing of mankind's
renewal. For a babe came from
a mountain, the pure virgin,
A young child the world
to renew all the peoples.
Amen.
Sunken in the waves of the sea's deepest waters,
the prophet Jonas implored you,
calm the tempest.
And I, O Christ,
punctured by the tyrant's arrow,
I call upon you,
from sloth now redeem me
Το πανάναχτος εξαφάλισαν τόπο,
απλή, απλή, απλή μέλοντος η κιτρωμένη,
παιδες τυράγον της θέων,
κομσαλγίαν, της η κατευθύρ,
άστε τον τόπες στόρτη,
Έχω σύνησε όλα σε προκυθώσει
We praise, bless, and worship the Lord, walking through fire unburned, the youths in the furnace, our types of the seal, virgin womb of the maiden.
when she gave birth past all nature to the Savior.
It was the same grace both from one.
from one wondrous power and raise the people to sing praise of the Master.
Σε παναπάβη και Σε την δόξα να αναπέμβομαι,
το Πατρί και το Υιό και το Υιό πνεύμα την Ήχεία
και εις τους αιώνας των αιωνών.
Αμήν.
Άσαν νοήεν έσαν το του Θήριον.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Let us pray to the Lord our God that we may be made worthy to hear the Holy Gospel.
Wisdom arise, let us hear the Holy Gospel. Peace be to you all.
The reading is from the Holy Gospel according to St. John.
little
be attentive.
Glory to you, O Lord. Glory to you.
At that time, Mary Magdalene came to the tomb early,
while it was still dark,
and saw that the stone had been taken away from the tomb.
So she ran and went to Simon Peter and the other disciple,
and the one whom Jesus loved, and said to them,
They have taken the Lord out of the tomb,
and we do not know where they have laid him.
Thank you.
Peter then came out with the other disciple and they went towards the tomb.
They both ran.
But the other disciple outran Peter and reached the tomb first and stooping to look in.
He saw the linen cloth laying there, but he did not go in.
Then Simon Peter came following him and went into the tomb.
He saw the linen cloth laying and the napkin which had been on his head not let
with the linen cloth, but rather rolled up in the place by itself.
Then the other disciple who reached the tomb first
also went in and his soul unbelieved.
For as yet they did not know the scripture
that he must rise from the dead.
Then the disciples went back into their home.
glory to you
having beheld the resurrection of christ let us worship the holy lord jesus the only sinless one
Your cross of Christ we venerate
and your holy resurrection we praise.
glorify. For you are our God. Apart from you we know no other. We call upon your name.
Come, all faithful, let us venerate the holy resurrection of Christ. For behold, through
the cross, joy has come to the whole world. Ever blessing, O Lord, let us praise his resurrection
for having endured the cross for us, he destroyed death by death.
Wash me thoroughly from my lawlessness and cleanse me from my sins.
Oh
Against you only have I sinned and done evil in your sight,
that you may be justified in your burns and overcome when you are judged.
You showed me the unknown and secret things of your wisdom.
You shall make me a joy and gladness.
My bones that were humbled shall greatly rejoice.
Turn your face from my sins and blot out all my transgressions.
Create in me a clean heart, O God, and renew a right spirit within me.
Me avaricis me apotu trotsopu su, ke to pnetman su to agionia dan Elisabewu.
Restore to me the joy of your salvation, and uphold me with your guiding spirit.
Deliver me from blood guiltiness, O God, the God of my salvation,
and my tongue shall greatly rejoice in your righteousness.
For if you desired sacrifice, I would give it.
You will not be pleased with all burnt offerings.
To God.
O Lord, in your good pleasure to Zion,
and let the walls of Jerusalem be built.
We offer you in San Christ our God,
as an offering of spiritual fragrances,
we receive it to the altar.
Send to us in the Trinity, praise the Holy Spirit.
And the star came and stood over the place
where the child was with Mary, his mother.
Then shall they offer young bolts on your altar,
and have mercy on me, O God.
Lord, Francis called himself
God Almighty, the others, all the ingredients of strength for us.
May the fall of you all and the Lord be moved.
Your glory has covered the heavens and the earth is filled with your blood.
Cover us and the shelter of your wings, right away from us,
with the forebring peace and our life.
Lord, you have mercy on us, your world, as a good and loving God, save us, so much.
For now and ever and to the ages of ages, Amen.
At the intercessions of the day of the Lord,
the sending forth and precious give us the spirit of the Lord,
Lord, and mercy of God,
God send the heavenly breath and nourish the whole world.
Lord God, Jesus Christ,
remember the fact of blessing and sacrifice us.
We will now bless this celebration,
exceding to your altar of all the heavens,
as a good and loving God.
Remember those who have offered his gifts
and those for whom they were offered in whole life,
blameless in the performance of the world of ministries.
For blessed and blessed is glorified in your holy,
majestic name of the Father,
Son, and Spirit, now and forever,
and ever, amen.
Holy God, Father, eternal,
holy, mighty Son,
for your holy, mighty Son,
for your holy, mighty Son, for your holy, mighty Son,
for your holy, mighty Son, for your holy,
glory to you.
You will go to the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit, now and the Father, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy, Lord, have mercy.
May Christ our God, who was born in the cave and rose from the dead,
through the prayers of His most pure Holy Mother, our Father, and the saints,
show us the most beautiful person of the temple, all the saints have mercy on us and save us for His good.
May we have mercy on us and save us for His good.
So...
Through the mercies of your only
O Michael and Lady Theotokos of the Virgin Mary
The power of the precious and life-giving cross
The protection of the honorable heavenly bodiless powers
The supplication of the honorable glorious prophet
And foran of John the Baptist
The holy, glorious and praiseworthy apostles
Our Father among the saints
the great
hierarchies
and ecumenical teachers, Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian,
and John Chrysostom, Athanasius, Sirius, John Merciful,
Patricks of Alexandria, Nicholas, Bishop of Myra,
Spirit-owned Bishop of Demetrius, Nectarius of Pentapolis,
the Wonder Workers, the Holy Glorious Great Martyrs,
George the Triumphant, Demetrius, the Mysterious Mother,
Theodore the Soldier, and Theodore the General,
Minas the Wonder Worker, Harambos, and Rephterios,
the Hayro Mothers
the holy, glorious, and victorious martyrs,
the glorious, great martyr, and laudable Ephemia,
the holy, glorious martyrs,
Thecla Barvara, Anastasia, Katerine Kiryaki,
Fotini Marina, Paraskevi, and Irene,
our venerable and God-bearing fathers,
the holy and righteous ancestors of Lord Joachim and Anna,
of the holy, righteous Joseph, betrothed David, the king,
and James, the brother of the Lord,
whose memory
we observe and all your saints.
We beseech you only, merciful Lord.
Hear our sinners who pray to you and have mercy on all.
Lord, have mercy. Lord, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Θεοτόκον και μητέρα του φωτός, εν ύμνης τιμών τες μεγαλύνομαι.
Ω, Ανανέ.
Μεγαλύτη, πληκτή μου, τωσκύριου, εγχασμία σπέτω στους πνεύμασους,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O-O
you call me
blessed
greater in honor
than the cherubim
and in glory
greater beyond
than the seraphim
you without
corruption
gave birth to call the word
and are truly
failed the whole coast
you do we magnify
um
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
He has shown strength with his arm, he has scattered the proud
in the imagination of their hearts.
Greater in honor than the cherubim,
in London, Wyoming, greater than the world.
oh
This is Zogadam, friend of mine.
He has helped his servant Israel in remembrance of his mercy.
With Gabriel we sing your praise.
With shepherds we give glory as we cry.
Mother of God, intercede with him.
Who was incarnate of you.
And we may be saved
I have begotten you from the womb before the morning star
The Lord swore and will not repent
The Father was well pleased
The Logos became flesh
And the Virgin gave birth to him
Who became a man
A star reveals him
Magi bow.
in worship shepherds marvel and creation rejoices
Maia
Glory to the Father and the Son.
and the Holy Spirit.
Blood and fire
and vapor of smoke.
Oh
These are the potions that joked for sun on the earth.
The blood.
is the incarnation of Christ.
The fire.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes
Bye.
of smoke is the Holy Spirit.
Oh
Is
And
The world with sweet fragrance
Grave
the mystery of your incarnation.
Oh, Lord, Lord.
in the
Lord.
Both now and ever
and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
You are highly blessed
all the
virgin mother of God,
for through him who was incarnate from you,
hell has been taken captive.
Adam recalled the curse slain.
He said, free death has been put to death,
and we have been given life.
Therefore with hymns we cry out,
Blessed are you, God.
Christ our God, who have been thus well pleased, glory to you.
We praise you.
We bless you, we worship you, we glorify you.
We give thanks to you for your great glory.
O Lord God, Lamb of God, Son of the Father,
who take away the sin of the world,
have mercy on us, you who take away the sin of the world.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ετύδιο μετά υπέρ των αδελφών ημών, των ιερών, ηραμανάχων, ηρωδιακών, και μοναχών και πάσης της εν Χριστώ ημών αδελφότητος.
Κύριε Λέισον, Κύριε Λέισον, Κύριε Λέισον.
Ετύδιο μετά υπέρ ελεύου ζωής, ηλίνης, ηγείας, οτιδείας, επισκέψεως, συγχωρήσεως και αφέσεως των αμαρτιών των δούλων του Θεού,
πάντων των ευσεβών και οθοδόξων χριστιανών, των κατοικούντων και παρεπιτιμούντων,
εν την πολιτάθη των ενωλητών επιτρόφων συνδρομητών και αφαιρέτων του Αγίου Ναουτού του.
Κύριε Ρέισον, Κύριε Ρέισον.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αντιλαβού στους ελεήσεων, Κύριε φύλαξον ημάς ο Θεός της ηχάρητη, Κύριε Ελεήσεων, την ημέρα πάσα, τελείαν, Αγία Νερυνικήν και Αναμάρτητον, παρά του Κύριου της Σώμας, Κύριε.
Look upon the humble and who with all deceiving eye I do behold all creation.
To you have we bowed the neck of our souls and bodies and implored you,
holy of holies, stretch forth your invisible hand from your early building place
and bless us all.
And if in any way we have sinned, either willingly or intentionally,
pardon us as much as you are good and love humankind,
granting us your good things in this age and years to come,
eternal life.
For your cities to show mercy and to save our Christ,
I guarantee you we give glory, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit,
now and forever in the ages of ages, amen.
wisdom
Blessed are you, Christ our God, always, now, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and forever, and
the holy glorious and praiseworthy apostles of our holy righteous ancestors of the Lord,
the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord,
of Saint Joseph, Saint David, the King, and of all the saints whose memory we celebrate today,
and of all your saints, have mercy on us and save us for his good and loves humankind.
Through the prayers of our holy fathers, Lord Jesus Christ, our God, have mercy on us and save us. Amen.
Let us sing to him who rose from the tomb, the author of our life.
for the
Destroying death by death,
He has given us the victory
and His great mercy.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Kyrie Eleison
For our country, for the president, all in public service, let us pray to the Lord.
For this city and every city and land and the faithful who live in them, let us pray to the Lord.
For favorable weather, for the abundance of the fruits of the earth and for peaceful times, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For the sick, the suffering, the captives, and their salvation, let us pray to the Lord.
Thank you.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
For to you belong all glory and worship to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
I will give thanks to you, O Lord, with my whole heart. I will tell of all your wondrous things.
Lord our God, whose dominion is incomparable and glory incomprehensible,
whose mercy is immeasurable enough,
for mankind and in the world.
Lord, look upon us
and upon this holy house
in your loving kindness
and grant to us
and to those who pray with us
their honor and mercy and compassion.
Through the intercessions
of the Theotokos
Savior, save us.
Excellency in manna is one
of the lima bar food
That's
Thanksgiving and majesty are his work,
and his righteousness continues unto ages of ages.
Through the intercessions of the Theotokos,
Savior, save us.
Foxa Patrice
Again and again in peace let us pray to the Lord.
Oh, my God.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us, and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed, and glorious Lady, the Theotokos,
and our Virgin Mary, with all the saints,
let us command ourselves and one another and our whole life to Christ our God.
For yours is a
dominion and yours is the kingdom and the power and the glory of the father and the son and
holy spirit now and forever and to the ages of ages
lord our god savior people bless our inheritance protect the fullness of your church sanctify
your soul out to be here your house glorify the man by your divine part forsake us not
God, You have granted us to offer this common praise in You, Son, and I promise unto You
three green your name your grander requests fulfill our lord the petitions of your servants
as may be of benefit to them granting us in the present nationals of your future
in the age to come return in life
this seed shall be mighty on earth save us oh son of god who are born of a virgin
as we sing to you.
Alleluia.
Glory and riches shall be in his house,
and his righteousness continues unto ages of ages.
So, sonima si etheu,
o ec parthenon te chris,
salontasi alleluia.
Oh
Αμήν.
Σταυρωθείς σε Χριστέ ο Θεός, θάνατο, θάνατον πατήσας
Ίσον της Αγίας Τριάδος, συνδοξαζόμενος το Πατρί και το Αγίο Πνεύματι σώσον ημάς
Είδα.
Thank you.
Μετά πάντων των Αγίων μνημονεύσανται σε αυτούς
και αλλήλους και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών
Χριστό το Θεό παραθώ μεθά
Ση Κύριε
Ό,τι αγαθός και φιλάνθρωπος Θεός υπάρχει
και εσύ την δόξαν αναπέμπομεν το πατρί και το Υιό
και το Υιό πνεύματι την Κυαή
και έστω σε όλα όσα
Master, Lord our God, who has established the orders and hosts of angels and archangels
in heaven to minister to your glory, grant that the holy angels may enter with us, that
together we celebrate the glory of your goodness and to you be.
Belong all glory, honor and worship, Father, Son, Holy Spirit, now and forever in the ages
of ages.
Amen.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Δευθε προσκυνήσω με και προσπέσω με Χριστό.
Σώσον η μας, Υιέ Θεού, ο Αναστάσεις εκ νεκρών,
Σόλον δώσ' στην αλληλία
Hallelujah.
When the women disciples of the Lord had learned from the angel
the joyful message of the resurrection,
casting away the ancestral condemnation,
triumphantly they said to the apostles,
Death has been despoiled, Christ God has risen, granting the world his great mercy.
I
Those who adore the stars were taught by the stars to worship you, the Son of Justice,
and to know you the day spring come on wide.
Lord, glory to you.
Annunciate the miracles to David.
the end
ancestor of God, O Joseph.
You saw the virgin pregnant.
You glorified with the shepherds.
You worshipped with the magi,
and you were warned by an angel
and treat Christ God to save our souls.
Oh,
is
Oh, no.
The pure virgin on this day
gives birth to one above me.
And to him who've gone approach, the earth now offers a heaven.
Angel fires along with shepherds, offer him glory.
I do follow the stars' light and make their journey.
For to us is born a young babe, a little child who before the ages is gone.
To kill you the eighth Oman.
For you are God, our holy, and to you we offer up glory to the Father and the Son and the
Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
O Holy God who is wrestling among the Holy Ones, praised by the seraphim with the tris holy
voice, glorified by the cherubim and worshipped by every celestial
power you have brought all things into being other nothing as you have paid away according to the
image and likeness don't involve the gifts of your grace you give us the one understanding to
the one who asks you overlook of the sinner and accept repentance as a way of your salvation you
have granted us your humble and unworthy servants to stand even at this hour before the glory of
your holy altar of sacrifice and to offer you worship and praise master accept that you say
i give him also from lips of our sinners and visit us in your goodness but you will volunteer
and volunteers.
And grant that we may worship you in holiness all the days of our lives.
Through the intercessions of the Holy Teotokos and all the saints.
Who please you throughout all the ages. Amen.
I guess I was I guess I was a kid
I guess I was a kid I guess I was a
translation of holy God holy mighty
holy mortal immersion us
I guess I'm not a solution
must
I'm going to go to the place.
Get a new one.
Get a new one now.
Glory to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Holy Immortal, have mercy on all.
I love you.
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.
Let us be attentive.
God is wondrous in his life.
the saints bless god in the churches wisdom the reading is from false letter to the galatians
let us be attentive
I would have you know that the gospel which was preached by me
is not according to man
for I did not receive it from man
nor was I taught it
but it came through a revelation
Jesus Christ
for you have heard
of my former life
in Judaism
how I persecuted the church of God
violently and tried
to destroy it
and I advanced in Judaism
beyond many of my
own age among my people
so extremely
zealous was I for the
traditions of my fathers
but when
I'm gone.
who had set me apart before I was born and had called me through his grace was
pleased to reveal his son in me in order that I might preach him among the
Gentiles I did not confer with flesh and blood nor did I go up to Jerusalem to
those who were apostles before me but I went away into Arabia and again
returned to Damascus then after three years I went up to Jerusalem to visit
Kephas and remained with him 15 days but I saw none of the other apostles except
James the Lord's brother
peace be to
Σοφία, όρθι ακούσομεν του Αγίου Ευαγγελίου ηλήνη πάση.
Εκ του καταμαθέων Αγίου Ευαγγελίου το ανάγνωσμα προσχωμένου.
Αναχωρήσα τόν των μάγων, ειδού άγγελος Κυρίου φαίνεται καθ' όνα.
Τος Ιωσήφ λέγω, αγέρθης παραλάβε των παιδίων και την μητέρα αυτού και φεύγε εις Αίγυπτων.
Καλή
Εκεί ως ανείπωση με λιγάρ ηρώνης ζήτην το πεδίο του απολέσε αυτό.
Ο δε αιγέρθης παρέλαβε το πεδίο και την μητέρα αυτού νυχθός.
και ανεφόρησεν εις Αίγυπτον και εις Αίγυπτον.
Είναι κύριος της τελεήτην η Ρόδου, είναι απληρώθητο ρήθεν υπό του Κυρίου, δια του προφήτου λέγοντες.
Εξ Αίγυπθου εκάλεσα τον Ιόν μου, τότε προηρωδής είδον
ότι εν επέχθητη υπό των μάγων, εθιμόθηλιαν
και αποστήλας εν ύλε πάντας τους παιδας τους εν βυθλεμ και εν πάση της
ορίς αυτής
αποδιεθούς
και κατοπτέρω
κατά των χρόνων
ον
Υκριρώσε παρά τον μάγον, τότε επτηρώσει το ρήθεν υπο Ιερεμίου του προφήτου λεγοντός.
Φωνή εν γάμα ακούστη θρήνος και κλαούθνος και οδύρμος παπολής.
Ραχιή κλαίουσα τα τέκνα αυτής και ούκ ήθελε παρακληθήνε ότι ούκ ήσοι.
Τελεύτησαντος δε του Ηρωδου ή του Άγγελος Κυρίου,
καθ' ονάρου φαίνεται το Ιωσήφ ένα Αιγύπτο λέγον.
εγώρ' τη σπαρά λάθω.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
ότι αρχιλαός βασιλεύει επί της Ιουδαίας, ο αντιερόντου του πατρός αυτού εφοβήθη εκεί απέωθην χρήμα της της.
Δεκατόναρ ανεχώρησεν εις τα μέρη της Γαλιλαίας
και έως τα μέρη της Γαλιλαίας.
Everything is from the Holy Gospel.
according to St. Magical.
Let us be attentive.
Glory to you, O Lord. Glory to you.
When the wise men departed, behold, the angel of the Lord appeared to Joseph in a dream and said,
Rise, take the child and his mother, and flee to Egypt, and remain there till I tell you,
for Herod is about to search for the child to destroy him.
And he rose and took the child and his mother by night and departed.
He started to Egypt and remained there until the death of Herod.
This was to fulfill what the Lord had spoken by the prophet,
Out of Egypt have I called my son.
Then Herod, when he saw that he had been tricked by the wise man,
was in the furious rage,
and he sent and killed all the male children in Bethlehem
and in all that region who were two years old.
or under, according to the time which he had ascertained from the wise man.
Then was fulfilled what was spoken by the prophet Jeremiah.
A voice was heard in Ramah, wailing and loud lamentation, Rachel weeping for her children.
She refused to be consoled because they were no more.
for when Herod died
Behold, an angel of the Lord appeared in a dream to Joseph in Egypt, saying,
Rise, take the child and his mother, and go to the land of Israel,
for those who sought the child's life are dead.
And he rose and took the child and his mother,
and went to the land of Israel.
But when he ordered, Ar-Helaios reigned over Judea in the place of his father.
He was afraid to go there and being warned in a dream, he withdrew to the district of Galilee and he went and dwelt in a city called Nazareth.
that what was spoken by the prophets might be fulfilled,
he shall be called a Nazarene.
to you.
Again, and count as time to fall down before you, we implore you, O good one who loves mankind,
that you have in regard to our prayer, may cleanse our souls and bodies from every deflament
of flesh and spirit and grant to us to stand before your holy table free of guilt
or condemnation grant also god to those who pray with us progress in life faith and spiritual
understanding grant that i always worship you with all love partake of your holy mysteries
without guilt or condemnation and be deemed worthy of your own celestial kingdom
that i were guarded by your might to describe glory to you to the father and the son and the
Holy Spirit now and forever and to the ages of ages.
No one bound by current desires and pleasures worthy to pursue you, to minister to you, the King of Glory,
for to serve you is great and awesome even for heavenly powers.
Yet because of your ineffable and immeasurable love for mankind, you impossibly immediately became man.
he was the master of all became our high priest
and delivered unto us the sacred service of this liturgical sacrifice without shedding of blood.
Indeed, Lord our God, your long reign over celestial and terrestrial,
born aloft on the cherubic throne, Lord the Seraphim and King of Israel,
the Holy Only, resting among the Holy Ones,
I now beseech you, who are not going to incline to hear,
look down upon me, your sinful and unprofitable servant,
and cleanse my soul and heart, and with your conscience,
enable me by the power of the Holy Spirit,
clothed with the grace of the priesthood to stand before your holy table
and celebrate the mystery of your holy and pure body.
and your precious blood. I come before you
with my head bowed and I implore you.
Turn not your face away from me nor reject me
from among your children but make me
your sinful and unworthy servant who
did you offer these gifts to you? For you are
the one who both offers and is offered the one who
is received and distributed. O Christ our God
unto you we offer up glory. With your
Father who is without beginning in your whole good life
and spirit now and forever and through the ages
of ages. Amen.
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia.
Let us who mystically represent the cherubim, and who sing the trisoli hymn to the life-caring
trinity, now lay aside every worldly care, so that we may receive the King of all, who
is invisibly escorted by the angelic hosts.
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia.
yeah, it and Chirovén mysticose iconizantes,
and is open dressage.
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia.
Having beheld the resurrection of Christ, let us worship the Holy Lord Jesus, the only
the sinless one who
your cross of Christ and the Holy Resurrection we praise and glorify for
you are our God we know no other it is your name we invoke come all the
faithful let us venerate the Holy Resurrection of Christ for behold to the
cross joy has come into the world ever blessing the Lord let us praise his
resurrection for enduring the cross for us he destroyed death by death
Thank you.
Brothers and sisters, let us love those who love us and let us love those who hate us.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
May the Lord, O God, remember us all in his kingdom, both now and forever,
into the edges of angels.
Amen.
May the Lord our God remember us all in his kingdom.
Boundary, Moundary, Stick, Erius.
Teos enli vesileye after.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
O
For this holy house and those who entered with faith, reverence, and fear of God,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
For a deliverance from all affliction, rather than your necessity,
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Kyrie elei son.
Dinime an pasant eleia na igien inrikin
ken amartiton para tu kiriou.
Eri som etha.
that the whole day may be perfect holy peace
Grant this, O Lord.
Let us ask of the Lord.
Let us, O Lord.
And let us ask for a Christian and to our life,
peaceful, without shame and suffering,
and for good defense before the awesome judgment,
seed of Christ.
We're out of this.
Lord God, O mighty, O Lord, and holy, accept the sacrifice of praise from those who call upon you with their whole heart.
even so excited
from us sinners, our supplication,
and bring it to your Holy Heart
of sacrifice, enable us to offer
your gifts and spiritual sacrifices
for our own sins and the failings of your people.
Demons, Lord, you find grace
in your sight, so
that our sacrifice may be all pleasing
to you, and the good spirit
of your grace may rest upon us
and upon these gifts here presented
and upon all of your people.
The author
of the
of the Lord.
Sin to Panagio kya gatho kya zopiosu pnevma tin inkiai
kya istus eonaston eonon.
Irini pahasi peace be to you.
Agapis omen al hilos in omena mia oma logis omen
that us love one another with oneness of mind we may confess.
God bless you.
O God, be gracious to me, sin and mercy on me.
For the last thing you need, O mortal loke lay his son.
Lord is my foundation, my refuge and my deliverer.
For those, for those in wisdom, let us be attentive.
Father, Almighty, creator of heaven and earth,
of all things visible and invisible,
and in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only begotten Son of God,
Begotten of the Father before all ages.
Light of light, true God of true God.
Begotten, not created.
Of one essence was the Father, whom all beings were made.
Who for us, man, and for our salvation,
came down from heaven and was incarnate by the Virgin Mary
and became man.
Who was crucified for our son, the Pontius Pilate,
and was buried.
According to the scriptures,
Yes, sir.
and in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the Creator of life,
who proceeds from the Father,
who together with the Father and the Lord is glorified,
who spoke to the prophets,
one holy Catholic and apostolic church,
I confess one baptism for the forgiveness of sins,
resurrection of death, and the might of age to come.
Amen.
storm
let us stand in all let us be attentive that we may present the holy offering in peace
the grace of our lord jesus christ and the love of god
and father and the communion of the Holy Spirit be with you.
On us come and ask our Deus, let us lift up our arms.
Ev home and prosto enquirio.
Ev charistis, omento kirio, let us give thanks unto the Lord.
It is proper and right to him you, to bless you, to praise you, to give thanks to you and to worship you in every place of your dominion.
For you, O God, are ineffable, inconceivable, invisible, incomprehensible, existing forever, forever the same.
You and your only begotten Son and your Holy Spirit, you brought us out of nothing into being.
And when we had fallen away, you raised us up again.
You left nothing undone until it's up to heaven and granted as you...
kingdom which is to come for all these things and we thank you in your only begotten son your
spirit for all things we know and do not know for blessings manifest and hidden and have been
bestowed on us we thank you also for his liturgy which you have deemed to receive from our hands
even though thousands of archangels and tens of thousands of angels stand around you the cherubim
and the seraphim six of many eyes soaring aloft upon their wings
singing the triumphal hymn exclaiming proclaiming and saying
together with his aggressive powers master who loves mankind we also exclaim and say
holy are you and most holy you and your only begotten son and your spirit holy are you
and more
Most Holy and Sublime, she said to all you,
Your soul, the word that you gave,
Your only begotten sons of everyone who believes in Him.
She did not perish, she got a eternal life.
When He had come and fulfilled for our sake,
the entire plan of salvation.
On the night in the days He was delivered up,
or rather when He delivered Himself up for the life of the world,
He took great His Holy Spirit,
blameless hands, and giving thanks and blessing He hallowed,
broke it and gave it to His disciples and apostles, saying,
Lávete, fallece tu tomo estito soma
To iperimon kilomenon, e safhes sin amartion,
Take, eat, this is my body, which is broken for you,
for the remission of sins.
Likewise, after partaking the supper, he took the cup saying,
Pietek saftupandes, tuto estito emamu,
totis kenis diethikis, to iperimon, kepolonekinomenon,
Isafil Sin Amartiyon
Drink of this, all of you.
This is my blood of the new covenant,
which is shed for you and for many
for the remission of sins.
Remembering, therefore, the saving commandment
always been done for our sake,
the cross, the tomb, the resurrection on the third day,
the ascension into heaven, the enthronement in the right hand,
and the second and the glorious coming again.
Das zeigt uns so, siebrus verumme, gottabanda ge-
upon thy your own of your own we offer to you in all and for all
once again we offer you this spiritual worship without shedding your blood and we
be seated on praying to send down your holy spirit upon us upon these gifts you
presented and make this bread the precious body of your christ
amen and then which is in this cup the precious blood of your christ
Amen
Amen, Amen, Amen.
So that they may be for those who partake of them for vigilance of soul, remission of sins,
communion of the Holy Spirit, fullness of the Kingdom of Heaven,
boldness before you and after judgment of God and pleasure.
Again we offer you this spiritual worship for all who have reposed in the faith,
forefathers, fathers, patriarchs, prophets, apostles, preachers, evangelists, martyrs, confessors, ascetics,
and every righteous spirit may perfect in faith.
Ex-Sereitos Dis Pana Giyas Achrandu
For Saint John the Prophet, Forerun and the Baptist,
the Holy Glorious and Praise-Wor the Apostles, for the Saints whose memory,
Joseph and David the King whose memory we celebrate today,
and of all your Saints through whose supplication visit us O God,
And remember fall asleep in hope resurrection to eternal life
Grant them rest, O God, who light your countenance keeps which again we beseech you, Lord, and all other
thoughts, bishops who are right to teach the word of the truth, the presbyter, or the acorn, and in Christ
and every priestly and monastic order. Again, we offer you this spiritual worship for the whole world,
for the holy Catholic and apostolic church, and for those living in pure, reverent lives,
for civil thorns and forces. You want that they may govern in peace, Lord, so that in their
tranquility, which you may live common, serenity, and lives, no piety and virtue.
Greatest name is the Holy Spirit, and you are always, now and forever.
I don't believe you're just saying.
What's my name?
ΑΛΟΝΤΗΣ
and remember those whom each of us has in mind,
and all your people.
Remember, Lord, the city in which we live,
and every city and land, and the faithful who live in them.
Remember, Lord, those who travel by land, sea and air,
the sick, the suffering, the captives, and their salvation.
Remember, Lord, those who bear fruit and do good works
in your holy churches, and those who are mindful of the poor,
and upon all send forth your mercies.
and grand that with one voice and one
horn we may glorify and praise your most honorable majestic name of the father and
son and holy spirit now and forever and to the ages of ages
yes
the
For your precious gifts here presented and consecrated,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord, have mercy.
many of us,
but have mighty keys.
Antigarapem,
simintinti,
and harin,
ketindoreantu agiu pneumatos,
veith omen.
Having asked for the unity of the faith,
and the communion of the Holy Spirit,
let us commend ourselves and one another,
and our whole life,
to Christ our God.
We entrust to the loving Master our whole life,
and hope and hubris.
and pray and implore you.
Grant us to partake of your heavenly
and awesome mysteries
from this sacred and spiritual table
with clear conscience for remission of sins,
forgiveness of transgressions,
the communal spirit,
inheritance of the kingdom of heaven
and boldness before you
for judgment or condemnation.
And grant us, Master,
with boldness and without condemnation
to dare call you the heavenly God,
Father, and to say,
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
And lead us not to temptation, but deliver us from evil.
Father, my dear, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is Jesus, my name is
ως εν ρουανώ και επί της γης των άρτων ημών των επιούσιων
δόσιμην σήμερον και άφεσιμην τα αφελήματα ημών
ως και εμείς σοφίαιμενς φελέτες ημών
και εμείες ενέγεσαι μας εις περασμών
αλλά ρίσσε ημάς από του πονηρού
ό,τι σου εστίνει η βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα του πατρός
και του Υιού και του Αγίου Πνεύματος
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
oh no see his me to you
basket for our simon to kill your clean home and let us bow our heads unto the
Lord we give thanks to invisible king who by your boundless power fashioned
the universe and in a multitude of your mercy where are all things in from
nothing into
being. Look down from heaven, O Master,
upon those who have bowed their heads
before you. For they have not bowed before
flesh and blood, but before you, dear awesome God.
Therefore, O Master, make smooth
and beneficial for us all, whatever lies
ahead according to the rich.
Sail with us who sail, travel with us who travel.
Heal the sick physician of our souls and bodies.
Amen.
Pros Homen, Ta-Agi Atis Agis,
let us be attentive, the holy gifts for the holy people of God.
The Lamb of God is apportioned, apportioned, and distributed,
apportioned, but no divided eating, and never consumed,
sanctifying those who partake of it.
Jesus Christos, Nikam.
The fullness of the Holy Spirit, blessed is the fervor of your sins,
always now and forever and today
of ages. Amen. The fervor of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
I believe and confess, Lord, a church who is the Christ, Son of the
living God, who came into the world to save sinners, of whom
I am the first. I also believe that this is truly your precious
body, that this is truly your precious blood. Therefore,
I pray to you, have mercy upon me and forgive my transgressions,
voluntary and involuntary, in order in need, knowledge, or ignorance,
and make me worthy without condemnation to dare call you.
Partake of your pure mysteries for remission of sins and eternal life. Amen.
Behold, I approach divine communion.
O Master, burn me not as I partake for you,
for you are fire consuming the unworthy, but cleanse me from every stain.
O Son of God, receive me today as a partaker of your mystical supper,
for I will not speak of the mystery to your enemies,
nor will I give you kisses, did Judas.
I'd like to see if I confess you, Lord.
Remember me in your kingdom.
Tremble, O man, as you behold the divine blood.
It is a burning coal that seers the unworthy.
The body of God both deifies and nourishes me.
It deifies the spirit and wondrously nourishes the mind.
You have smitten with the warning of Christ,
and by your divine arrows you have changed me.
But burn up with spiritual fire my sins,
and grant me to be filled with delight in you.
So in living for joy I may magnify your good one, your two comings.
How shall I, you am unworthy, enter into the splendor of your saints?
if I should dare to enter into the bridal chamber,
my vesture will condemn me since it is not a wedding garment
and being bound up I shall be cast out by the angels
cleanse the Lord the filth of my soul and save me
as you are the one who loves mankind
in your love Lord cleanse my soul and save me
master who loves mankind
Lord Jesus Christ my God
let not this holy gift be to my judgment because I am unworthy
but rather for the purification and sanctification
both soul and body and the pledge of the life and the kingdom to come
it is good for me to cleave unto God and to place him.
him the hope of my salvation.
O son of God, receive me today as a partake of your mystical supper, for I will not speak
of the mystery to your enemies, nor I will give you a kiss as did Judas, but like the
thief I confess you, Lord.
Remember me in your kingdom.
O God, be gracious to me, a sinner, and have mercy on me.
Brothers and servants, please forgive my sins.
Brothers and sisters, please forgive my sins.
Behold, I approach Christ our King and our God, Anthony the unworthy Presbyter receives
the Holy Body of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, for the mission of my saints and for
life everlasting.
Amen.
Behold, I approach Christ again our King and our God, Anthony the unworthy Presbyter receives
the Holy Blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, for the mission of my saints and for
life everlasting.
Amen.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Amen, Amen, Amen.
This has touched my lips, has pushed my soul and cleansed my sins.
Glory to you, God, I hope, glory to you.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, and to the ages of ages. Amen.
Having beheld the Resurrection of Christ, let us worship the Holy Lord Jesus,
the only sinless one. We venerate your cross, O Christ,
and the Holy Resurrection in the presence of God.
For you are our God, we know no other. It is your name, we invoke.
will come all the faithful in us, Father,
we do.
the holy resurrection of Christ.
For behold, through Christ,
you are coming to the world.
Ever blessing the Lord
as praise His resurrection
for enduring the cross
for us to destroy death by death.
Praise the Lord from the heavens.
Thank you.
Praise him in the highest.
Alleluia.
Praise him, all his angels.
Praise him, all his powers.
Alleluia.
Praise him, Son of God.
Praise him, all your stars at night.
Alleluia.
Praise Him, you are.
highest heavens and you waters that are above the heavens
let them praise the name of the Lord for he spoke and they came into being he
commanded and they were created.
Alleluia.
He established them forever and ever.
He made the Lord and sent it to God.
Alleluia.
Praise the Lord from the earth.
Praise him, you see monsters and all deeps.
Alleluia.
Fire and hail and snow and ice and storm wind, things that do his word. Alleluia.
Mountains and mountains, fruiting trees and mountains. Alleluia.
Metafor, O Theopisteos,
Kiarapis, proselfete with fear of God.
with faith and love,
journey.
Handmaiden of God, Petrula, receives the holy body
and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
for the mission of our sins and life-lasting. Amen.
The Handmaiden of God, Catherine, receives the holy body
and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, for the mission of our sins and life-lasting.
Amen. Servant of God, Rachel, receives the holy body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
mission of his sins
of everlasting
Amen.
The handmaiden of God, Lydia, receives the holy body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
for remission of her sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
Servant of God, Gregorius, receives the holy body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
for remission of his sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
Handmaiden of God, Barbara, receives the holy body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
for remission of her sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
The handmaiden of God, Catherine, receives the holy body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ,
for the mission of the saints
Amen.
The handmaiden of God receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ on the mission of our sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
Servant of God, Valentine receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and Savior
Jesus Christ on the mission of his sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
The handmaiden of God, Elizabeth receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and
Savior Jesus Christ on the mission of our sins and for life everlasting.
Amen.
The servant of God, Lucas receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and Savior
Jesus Christ, permission of his sins and
for life everlasting. Amen.
Servant of God John receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and the Savior of Jesus Christ.
On the mission of his saints and the life of last thing. Amen.
The handmaven of God Mary receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and the Savior of Jesus Christ.
Servant of God of Angelus receives the Holy Body and the Blood of our Lord and the Savior of Jesus Christ.
On the mission of his saints and the life of last thing. Amen.
Amen.
the servant of God the other who receives the Holy Body and the blood of our Lord and
save Jesus Christ for the mission of his sins and for life everlasting. Amen.
Servant of God Isaiah receives the Holy Body and the blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ for the mission of his sins and for life everlasting. Amen.
Sosonotheos ton laonsu, kev logis on ting thironomi ansu, save all your people and bless
your inheritance.
We have received Thy hand when we see it.
We have found us by the earth.
He exalts the God of the heavens, the Holy Spirit.
Bless you, the God.
Αμήν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
and protect us oh god by your grace having prayed for perfect holy peaceful and sinless day
let us command ourselves and one another in our whole life to christ our god
we give thanks to your master who loves mankind the benefactor of our souls that even on this
very day you have made us worthy of your heavenly and immortal mysteries make straight our path
for it if I listen your fear.
guard our life, make secure our step
through the prayers and supplications of the glorious Theotokos
and of all your saints.
For you are our sanctification and to you we give glory
to the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Let us go forth in peace.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Hear ye and lay ye song.
All over.
blesses those who bless you and sanctifies
those who put your trust in you. Save your
people and bless your inheritance.
Protect the whole body of your church. Sanctify
those who love the beauty of your house.
Glorify them in return by your divine power.
And forsake us not who have set our hope in you.
Grant peace to your world, to your churches,
to our clergy, to our civil leaders,
to the armed forces and to all your people.
For every good and perfect gift is from above
coming down from you, the Father of lights.
To you we give glory, thanksgiving
and worship. To the Father and
the Son and the Holy Spirit,
it.
now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Christ our God, your former Lord,
prophet, your former Father,
and your Father, and your Father,
O.
Amen.
May the blessing of the Lord and his mercy
come upon you by his divine grace and love for mankind
always now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Glory to your God, glory to you.
May he who was born in a cave and lay in a manger
for
our salvation and rose from the dead Christ our true God through the
intercessions of his all-pure and all-immaculate Holy Mother the power of
precious and life-giving cross the protection of the honorable bodiless
powers of heaven as supplications of the honorable glorious prophet and forerunner
John the Baptist the holy glorious and praiseworthy apostles the holy glorious
and triumphant martyrs righteous and God-bearing fathers the holy and
righteous ancestors of Lorde,
of all,
and of all,
the holy and righteous Joseph the betrothed David the king and James
Jacob was the brother of the Lord whose memories we observe and of all the Saints
have mercy on us and save us for his good and loves humankind
Amen.
All the way through.
Christmas, guys.
Good?
Awesome.
You enjoy it?
Yes?
Did you get gifts?
Any coal in your stockings?
No?
Not this year, right?
Because you were good kids.
Came to church every Sunday.
So Santa loves you.
All right.
What?
you didn't look
You haven't opened the stocking yet?
Okay.
You're a patient girl, I guess, huh?
I opened it yesterday.
All right.
Well, thank you for bringing the kids.
It's very cold out there.
I wasn't expecting too many people to show up,
but thanks for bringing them sacrificially.
Since we have time, the liturgy was quite long,
I mean, short today.
I'm going to do a Greek sermon.
Και τώρα θα πω λίγο πραγματικά στο Ιγγλίο.
μέρη του κόσμου και ακολουθώντας το αστέρι οδηγήθηκαν στον νεογεννητό Κύριο και Σωτήρα μας.
Το αστέρι αυτό όπως λέει ο Άγιος Ιωάννης ο Χρυσόστομος δεν ήταν ένα συνηθισμένο αστέρι
Αλλά
ένα θεϊκό σημείο που φαίνονταν τόσο τη νυχτά όσο και την ημέρα
και κινούνταν για τα τους οδηγήσεις στον Μεσσία.
Το οποίο θαυμαστό όμως δεν είναι το αστέρι αλλά η ικανότητα.
Ικανότητα των μάγων να το δουν.
Ο Ηρώδης, οι ιεραίες και ο άλλος δεν μπορούσαν να διακρίνουν το φως.
Παρότι γνωρίζαν τις προφητείες,
ο φόβος, ο θυμός και η στενοκεφάλεια τους κρατών.
κρατήσαν στο σκοτάδι, όπου όμως υπάρχει φως, το σκοτάδι προσπαθεί να το πολεμήσει
γι' αυτό και η Αγία οικογένεια αναγνωρίστηκε να καταφύγει στην Αίγυπτο.
Σήμερα ο Χριστός είναι αναμέσα μας.
The church and our home are becoming Bethlehem.
And the stars are burning above every heart that is longing to bear the fire and to burn the fire.
Thank you.
today I want us to
Pay attention to three things.
Finding the Messiah.
Returning through a different way.
And coming out of Egypt.
Those three things are the central messages of the gospel from a perspective of spiritual life.
Not historically, but spiritually, what they actually mean for us.
finding
the Messiah. Those who were able to find the Messiah did not find them by their own intellect,
they did not find by their abilities, by their craftiness, by their ways in the world. The
shepherds were visited by the angels the magi the kings were led by a heavenly
light
a star that was visible both during the day and at night,
and it traveled along the path towards the Messiah,
and it was hanging over the child when they found him.
St. John Chrysostom says that this light was not just a heavenly body.
It wasn't a star.
It was the light of God leading those who were enlightened by the light.
who could see in the darkness of this world,
were led by the light of God to the light of the world,
that is Christ himself, to show where he was born.
The priests and the others, the leaders of Israel,
were supposed to know when the Messiah would be born and where.
and that is why Herod
counsels them to find out
where
they were born. He was born. But he can't find on his own where the Messiah is because
he is in darkness. And even the priests and the Pharisees and others couldn't find him.
They couldn't point out. And the Magi did not obey the command of this dark king to
show where the Messiah was because they were instructed by God
to return by another way.
And that's what I want second to pay attention.
When we find the Messiah, our way changes.
Father Lev Gillet points out to this one sentence.
They went home by another way.
they came by one way before they had found the Messiah
But once they found the Messiah, their life changed.
The way of their life changed.
They returned to their home by another way.
Because they have found the way and the destination.
Father Lev says, Christ our Lord is the way and the destination at the same time.
If you are on the way, on a different way,
than what your way has been all this time,
than you are with Christ because he is their destination.
So the Magi's finding the Messiah had a total transformation of their lives
and the way of their life changed.
So therefore, when we celebrate Christmas year after year after year
and we remain on the same way, we should ask a question to ourselves.
When we celebrate Christmas, do we actually find the Messiah?
Or we are like Herod, wondering in the darkness and wondering whether it is even true.
The true sign of finding the Messiah is the change of life.
And the change of life is not an instantaneous thing.
we are not all St. Paul's
that we can be going that direction
and then all of a sudden we see the light
and we
start going that direction. When the Magiists found the Messiah, they returned home in another way.
It was one step at a time, going towards their home on that unknown way, on that unknown path
that they had to discover every day what is the right path for them to go home.
returning from Egypt
this is my favorite topic
returning from Egypt of Israel.
Because once they were visited by God,
once Moses instructed them to leave Egypt and go home,
they also went by another way that was unfamiliar to them.
When they were wandering in the desert,
and complaining about it,
is because they were experiencing the...
unknown every single day. They were asked to trust Moses and God, enter into the desert of the unknown.
So when we find the Messiah, the other way, the way that is given to us is not that well-throdened
way that we just get in our SUVs and just dart through the dust into the promised land.
We walk in the dark.
We walk in the cold.
We walk in hunger and thirst
with scorpions and snakes surrounding us.
We lose hope sometimes.
We complain.
We rebel against God.
And that is the life of repentance.
It's a hard work.
That's why the liturgy is called liturgia,
which means the work of the people.
Are we working in our lives to find the Messiah,
open our hearts so that the light can shine there
and show us where the Messiah is?
And when we find him, do we change our lives
from our own willingness and our own will and desires
into the will of God?
Do we change?
if we don't then we
just celebrate Christmas like everybody else. We buy gifts for each other and we forget in the
process that Christ is the central image of Christmas, not the gifts that we give to each
other. That Christ is seeking for the gift of transformation. That's what he's looking for.
That this year we can say that we are different than we were last year.
that next year at this time we will be different than we are today.
In our journey that we have gotten closer to the promised land,
which is the kingdom of God.
That we have been walking, not stalling and stagnating in our daily routines.
That we have found the way and we are going towards the city of God.
For the Lord is the Lord.
the land of sin. The last thing I'll say which is is very common thing nowadays
the most common thing is the concept of refugees. Everywhere on this planet there
are refugees living from one country to another for political reasons, for
for economic reasons, for
geopolitical reasons, for reasons of war and famine,
and all the reasons are there, and people are constantly shifting,
moving from one country to another for one reason, to survive.
To survive.
Today, our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, is showing us
that he even was not exempt from
being a refugee for survival purposes.
Joseph today took
the baby and his mother, the gospel
said, and fled to Egypt.
They were refugees like
all the refugees of the world we have today.
And they stayed there with a dream of their
homeland
Every refugee, even if they come to the best country and they have the best economic,
our mind is always back in the old country.
Sometimes we think it's better over there, but we still stay here.
Because really it's better here.
But our homeland is that part of our life.
That we dream one day we'll return to Jerusalem.
them.
The Israelites
all over the world had that expression,
many of you have heard,
next year in Jerusalem.
Because that is their homeland.
Our Lord and Savior and Joseph and Mary
probably said that expression many times in their heads
when they were in Egypt.
Next year back in Jerusalem.
Because that was the prophecy.
I will take my son out of Egypt.
but Egypt also has a sense
of spiritual meaning.
Egypt is the land, according to the Bible,
the land of sin, of corruption, of idolatry.
And we also ought to leave Egypt.
In order for us to enter into the kingdom of God,
instead of saying, next year in Athens,
or next year in Armenia,
I should be saying next year
in the kingdom of God.
Because here, I am a refugee.
If you read the church fathers,
they say, we Christians
are temporarily travelers
and refugees in this world.
And the fact that we are suffering
is God helping us
to constantly keep our minds
on the exodus.
that wonder
we will also leave this life of refugee in this world
and we will travel into the promised land
which is the kingdom of God.
So let us reflect on these three, four things
which is finding the Messiah
by allowing the light of God to shine and illumine our hearts and our minds
so we can actually see.
When we find the Messiah, do not resist change.
embrace the other way that has been presented to us,
the way of Christ,
because we need to reach the destination,
because we are refugees like our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ.
Literally and mystically,
as the citizens of the kingdom of God,
we're waiting for that time.
We can leave Egypt.
the sin and the
corruption of this world
and enter into the heavenly
presence of God
in the presence of our Lord
and Savior Jesus Christ
now and forever.
Amen. Thank you.
That wasn't too bad, right?
Just kidding.
Amen.
Thank you.
Oh
İzlediğiniz için teşekkür ederim.
Субтитры создавал DimaTorzok
O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O, O
Oh
I'll stop now.
I don't know anything about it.
I'm going to eat a little bit too.
This is my purple kids.
Purple show.
I'm not
Thank you.
six
What's the matter?
I said I was going to replace that.
I was going to replace that.
With what?
I'm sitting here on table.
She was like, Blacker didn't deal with all of that.
Mom drumming?
I almost said mom drumming.
What?
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Hey, cause...
Can you stop, please?
Stop!
Dude.
Dude. She was just slapping me.
Like a little...
Thank you.
Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on!
E aí
Gracias.
Thank you.
So,
All right.
E aí
Thank you.